# **Ahmed Rizk Tolba**

**Mobile:** 01147760632 - 01204921114 **Address:** Toukh - Qalubiya – Egypt

> **E-mail:** rizkahmed1@gmail.com Linkedin: ahmed-rizk

### Personal Profile

**Nationality** Egyptian **Marital status** Married Military service Exemption Date of Birth 12-Aug-1990

Gender Male

## **Career Summary**

Senior Software Testing Engineer and ISTQB Certified, currently leading the non functional testing activities at Capiter Company. Experienced in manual testing for many Web, Mobile applications as well as automation testing through many Frameworks like Selenium Webdriver (with Java, Maven, TestNG, Appium), Katalon Studio, Cypress, TestCafe and Robot including POM and BDD using Cucumber. also Experienced performance testing using Apache JMeter.

Now Targeting a challenging position as Software Testing Lead that will take full advantage of my education, and acquired Skills in Software Testing field to positively influence company operation, performance and profitability and earn more experience.

## **Education**

Benha University University

Shoubra Faculty of Engineering College

Bachelor of Communication and Grade

**Electronics Engineering** 

Degree Good (74.31%)

Year 2012

### **WORK EXPERIENCE:**

#### 5/2021 – Present Senior Automation Testing Engineer, Capiter Company

#### **Key Responsibilities:**

- Leading team of three automation and performance engineers.
- ➤ Participate in Agile team meetings to handle and estimate backlog and plan sprint (millstones) work.
- > Participate in automation tool selection.
- Build and maintain automation framework using Katalon Studio tool.
- ➤ Identify test cases that may be candidates for Automation each sprint.
- > Assign tasks to team members as per their qualifications and skills.
- > Troubleshoot the automation problems, searching and investigating for proper solutions.
- ➤ Participate in implementing the continuous integration process for the automation with the help of the SRE team using GitHub and GitHub actions.
- > Creating and running Performance Scripts using Jmeter.
- > Train and guide other team members for automation and performance.
- ➤ Utilize the positive and open attitude promoted across the teams to discuss problems and provide support to others.

### ♦ 5/2020 – 5/2021 Senior Software Quality Control Engineer, Lagorta Company

#### **Key Responsibilities:**

- ➤ Participate in team meetings to handle and estimate backlog and plan sprint (millstones) work.
- > Participate in creating and reviewing Test cases and TDDs.
- Execute test cases manually and report Bugs (using JIRA) and follow up with the development team.
- ➤ Identify test cases that may be candidates for Automation.
- Build and maintain Automation Framework based on (Java, Maven, TestNG, Page Object Model Design pattern).
- Monitor every phase of the software development process to ensure design quality, making sure that the software adheres to the standards set by the development company.
- Breaking up the entire process into goals such as verifications, activities, measurements, abilities, and commitments
- > Train and guide other team members in automation processes.
- ➤ Utilize the positive and open attitude promoted across the teams to discuss problems and provide support to others.

## ♦ 1/2020 – 5/2020 Senior Software Quality Control Engineer, Siliconexpert Technologies an Arrow company, Egypt

#### **Key Responsibilities:**

- Primarily responsible for individual contribution in testing cases based on released content by performing manually and automated (Selenium and JMeter) tests under lead supervision to ensure they fulfill marketing requirements
- Monitor every phase of the software development process to ensure design quality, making sure that the software adheres to the standards set by the development company.
- ➤ Breaking up the entire process into goals such as verifications, activities, measurements, abilities, and commitments
- ➤ Developing, documenting, and implementing applicable QA processes and procedures to provide more effective quality methods within the group in support of providing quality products.
- Implement the new automation cases to Automation plan.
- Run and maintain the existing Automation plans based on new sprint modifications.
- > Confirm system behavior based on Automation results for staging and production server for each release.
- ➤ Involves in the Performance process by preparing and implementing the new script scenarios by recording or manually adding.
- Perform load and stress testing.

## ♦ 2/2017 – 12/2019 Junior Software Quality Control Engineer, Siliconexpert Technologies an Arrow company, Egypt

#### **Key Responsibilities:**

- Review of software requirements actively using every function and tool of the software solution to develop a deeper understanding of the product and how it works
- ➤ Design test methods, test cases and other documentation for functional and regression testing under leader supervision.
- > Executes engineering test cases or baseline/integration test cases and ensures that results are recorded.
- ➤ Identifies defects consistently and clearly that defects can be reproduced by the development team.
- > Works with development as required to help reproduce issues and to ensure defects are understood and valid.
- Preparation of test reports.

## 6/2013 –1 /2017 Senior Data Engineer, Siliconexpert Technologies an Arrow company, Egypt

#### **Key Responsibilities:**

- ➤ Review the Customer requirement in terms of Environmental data and create a plan for the delivery.
- ➤ Collecting the Environmental data manually or by using extracting tools or by contacting the manufacturer.
- ➤ Handle daily customer requests through the ticket system.
- ➤ Adding new software tools to help in extracting the data to increase productivity and increase data quality.
- Involve in the data update process.
- Using Exporting and importing tools in daily data development.
- > Follow with other team members to help and train and to confirm meeting the due date of each task.

## **Technical Experiences**

- ISTQB Foundation Level certified.
- Involvement in software Testing Life Cycle.
- Experienced in Functional Testing, Non-Functional Testing, and user acceptance test
- Experience in Bug Tracking Process, Familiar with Bug Reporting and tracking using Jira tool.
- Experience in Functional testing (Test case design, test execution and collecting test data).
- Experience in many testing Automation Frameworks using POM and BDD like:
  - Selenium Web Driver (Java, Maven, TestNG)
  - Katalon Studio
  - Cucumber
  - Cypress
  - TestCafe
  - Robot
- Experience in implementing CI/CD process using GitHub, GitHub Action and Jenkins
- Experience in Performance testing using the following tools:
  - Apache JMeter
  - BlazeMeter
- Familiar with Monitoring tools like Grafana and Kibana.
- Experience in API manual Testing using Postman.

- Experience in API Automation Testing using Rest Assured and cypress.
- Knowledge on SQL to conduct database Testing.
- Knowledge on Oracle and MySQL to conduct database Testing.
- Familiar to the PostgreSQL database.
- Familiar with the SOLR Index.
- Familiar to using Slack.

## **Personal Skills**

- Interactive and fast to learn new technologies.
- Good Communication skills.
- Ability to self-development.
- Adapt well to changes and pressures in the workplace.
- Ability to make fast and reliable decisions about how to solve problems.
- Ability to teach, train and share information with others.
- · Good focus on technical details.
- Very dedicated.
- · Accept responsibility willingly.

## Languages

- Arabic: Mother Tongue.
- English: Good Spoken & Written.